Alan Leverenz

New York, NY 10025 • awww.linkedin.com/in/alan-leverenz
https://alanleverenz.github.io
• https://alanleverenz.github.io
• https://github.com/AlanLeverenz

Full Stack Web Developer I Technical Leader

Full Stack Web Developer experienced in internet-based systems, digital workflows, client interfaces, middleware scripting, data conversions, and database development. Great organizational, technical, and communication skills, plus a deep desire to learn have brought success as a client services manager for a SaaS/PaaS ad management service, product manager for type design and special effects software, systems integrator applying XSL conversions for business messaging and managed file transfers for advertising assets, and consultant to publishers on color management.

Collaborated with internal and external teams to analyze markets, project plan, and produce results that meet business objectives. Awarded a certificate in full stack web development from Columbia University and have continued studies to expand and deepen knowledge of leading-edge tools, JavaScript libraries, and frameworks. Enjoy discovering, problem-solving, persisting, and meeting users' needs.

Core Technical Competencies

React, NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, MySQL, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript ES6, JQuery, JSON, XML, XSL, FileMaker, Perl, C, AppleScript, Microsoft Excel, Adobe Creative Cloud

Areas of Expertise

Web Development	Database Development	Product Management
Systems Integration	Team Leadership	Consulting Services
Market Analysis	Strategic Planning	Stakeholder Communications

Web Development Projects

Sentiment I http://news-polarizer.herokuapp.com/ I Full Stack Developer MERN app for collecting and analyzing newspaper content for sentiment. Technologies. React, MongoDB, Express, NodeJS, JavaScript ES6, RapidAPI, IBM Cloud NLU

Web-Scraper I https://aqueous-forest-71988.herokuapp.com I Full Stack Developer NodeJS app for scraping world news headlines and articles from the Jerusalem Post. Technologies. Handlebars, MongoDB, Express, NodeJS, Cheerio, JavaScript

Vacay I https://alanleverenz.github.io/Vacay/ I Full Stack Developer
Web app for providing information for travelers to selected countries.
Technologies. HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Firebase, Google Maps, NYTimes API, AccuWeather API, DataFixer Currency API

Experience

Adstream, New York, NY Client Services Manager

2016 - 2019

Sustained and built ad delivery services for the Americas aligned with strategies for sustaining and developing ad delivery and related advertising workflow services.

- Managed a support services staff that provided technical assistance to clients including advertising agencies, retail companies, brands, and publications.
- Participated in the strategic planning, preparation and release of marketing campaigns for new

- products optimizing visibility and the marketability of the product.
- Executed annual and monthly agreements for over 500 publishers in the United States.
- Developed a database storing US publishers and their properties for developing targeted marketing campaigns and sharing with SalesForce.

Dubsat, New York, NY

2007 - 2016

VP Print Solutions, Finance (June 2015 – November 2016)

Accountable for sustaining and building ad delivery services for the Americas and assist in Dubsat's worldwide strategies for building and developing ad delivery and related advertising workflow services.

- Integrated the ad delivery service with third party vendors servicing the advertising industry.
- Developed databases for agencies and retailers to connect with the web enterprise service.

Technical Sales, Software Engineer (March 2007 – June 2015)

Supported and developed solutions for client workflows and provided technical sales support for the sales and CSR teams.

- Integrated advertiser and publisher systems with the Adsend ad delivery enterprise service.
- Developed FileMaker databases for agencies and retailers to fulfill their ad campaigns. The solutions utilized a Java application managing a RESTful XML API for exchanging messages with an enterprise cloud, utilizing a Saxon XSL engine.
- Worked closely with the sales team in solving client needs, identifying target markets.
- Revised existing automated solutions to adapt to new system infrastructures resulting in improving operational efficiencies significantly.

Associated Press, New York, NY

1994 - 2007

Ad Management, System Integrations

Developed middleware solutions for national brand advertisers and retail companies to interface their media buy campaigns with the Associated Press Ad Management service.

- Provided system integration solutions for enabling media buys and asset deliveries for clients using Adsend Ad Management services.
- Integrated advertiser and publisher systems to enable automated ad deliveries with the Adsend service, using Perl scripts and XSL transformations.
- Member of the AdsML Technical Workgroup that created the AdsML Framework for XML-based business messages in the advertising industry.

Technology Marketing

Served as imaging products manager for the Technology Marketing department. Responsible for maintaining an OEM relationship with ECRM for installing imaging devices for implementing color solutions at newspaper publisher sites.

- Assisted sales in targeting and selling to prospective publishers and publisher groups.
- Applied ICC-based color solutions at numerous publisher sites. Provided Photoshop training for photographers and editors, calibrated imaging devices and set press ink density standards for accurate color reproduction.

Additional Related Experience

Letraset USA, New York, NY

Software Product Manager

Product Manager for two Manager

Product Manager for two Mac-based graphics software products named FontStudio and LetraStudio. Managed 3rd party software developers with oversight for Beta programs and technical documentation.

Education

Ed.D Candidate, Teachers College, Columbia University Master of Education, Teachers College, Columbia University Master of Music, Teachers College, Columbia University Bachelors of Music, San Diego State University

Certifications

Certification in Full Stack Web Development, Columbia University, Trilogy. **National Coach Certification**. American Youth Soccer League.

Community Involvement

Unity of New York. President, Board of Trustees **Westside Soccer League**. Regional Coach Administrator and Trainer. **New York Road Runners**. Active member.